American Philosophical Society Archives. Record Group IIi. 1897 APS.Archives.IIi APS.Archives.IIi
American Philosophical Society
- Papers
  - Letter to [Isaac Minis] Hays, Oct. 9, 1897; 9-1/2x5-3/4; Heilprin, Angelo, 1853-1907
    Phila., A.L.S. 1p. Will try to attend meeting on Monday.
  - Letter to J [sic] Minis Hays, Oct. 9, 1897; 11x8; Houston, Edwin J. (Edwin James), 1847-1914
    Phila., Typed L.S. 1p. Cannot attend Nansen meeting. Kennelly may attend.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, Oct. 11, 1897; 10-1/2x8-1/4; Methodist Episcopal Book and Publishing House
    Toronto, Typed L. 1p., end. Inquires about Hilprecht's papers on Old Babylonian inscriptions. For printed papers, see: APS Transactions, vol. 18, pp. 5-54, 221-282.
  - Note to the American philosophical society, Oct. 11, 1897; 3-1/2x5-1/2; Williams, Talcott, 1849-1928
    Phila., A.N. 1p., end., and add. Change of address.
  - Letter to [Isaac Minis] Hays, Oct. 12, 1897; 9-1/4x6; Field, Robert Patterson, -1931
    Phila., Typed L.S. with stamp 1p. Enc. wanting Sends his paper on "The span of life." For printed paper, see: APS Proceedings vol. 36, pp. 420-424.
  - Letter to the [American philosophical society], Oct. 12, 1897; 7x4-1/2; Mineralogische und petrographische mitteilungen
    Vienna, A.L.S. G[ustav] Tschermak 1p. Enc. wanting In German Sends receipts. Thanks for books. Change of address.
  - Letter to [Isaac Minis] Hays, Oct. 12, 1897; 11x8-1/2; Pennsylvania. Governor (1895-1899: Hastings)
    Harrisburg, Typed L. 1p. Exchange of publications.
  - Letter to [Isaac Minis] Hays, Oct. 12, 1897; 8-1/2x5-1/2; Rosengarten, J. G. (Joseph George), 1835-1921
    Paris, A.L.S. 4p. Encs. wanting Sends Ellis & Elvey's bill for rebinding almanac. Refers to Bertin and French exchanges, the library's new quarters.
  - Letter to [William] Pepper, Oct. 13, 1897; 7-1/4x4-1/2; Jastrow, Morris, 1861-1921
    Phila., A.L.S. 2p. and end. Concerns his paper on the origin of the Hebrew Sabbath.
  - Letter to [Isaac] Minis Hays, Oct. 13, 1897; 9x5-3/4; MacCalla & co.
    Phila., L. 1p. Concerns G.H. Ashley's Paper on the geology of Arkansas For printed paper, see: APS Proceedings vol. 36,pp. 217-318.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, Oct. 13, 1897; 3-1/2x5-1/2; University of Pennsylvania
    [Phila.,] L. on postal card 1p., end., and add. Gives address of J.Y. Burk.
  - Letter to J [sic] Minis Hays, Oct. 13, Oct. 18, 1897; 10-1/2x8; United States. Superintendent of Documents
    Washington Printed L. filled in in MS. 2 items 2p. Concerns requests for public documents.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, Oct. 14, 1897; 8x5; Mathews, R. H. (Robert Hamilton), 1841-1918
    Parramatta, New South Wales, A.L.S. 4p. Enc. wanting Concerns papers on rock carvings and paintings. Asks about becoming a "Corresponding Member." For printed paper, see: APS Proceedings, vol.36, pp. 466-478.
  - Letter to J[sic] Minis Hays, Oct. 15, 1897; 5-1/2x8; Houston, Edwin J. (Edwin James), 1847-1914
    Phila., Typed L.S. 1p. Enc. wanting Sends catalogue. Refers to Library Committee.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, Oct. 15, 1897; 8-1/4x5-1/2; Museo de La Plata
    La Plata, Printed L. filled in in MS. 1p., end. In French Exchange of publications.
  - Letter to [Isaac Minis] Hays, Oct. 15, 1897; 9x5-3/4; Mercer, Henry Chapman, 1856-1930
    Doylestown, Pa., Enc. wanting Sends MS. and illustrations of his paper on Pennsylvania-German franktur. For printed paper, see: APS Proceedings vol. 36, pp. 424-433.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, Oct. 15, 1897; 8-3/4x5-3/4; Uppsala Universitetsbibliotek
    Upsala, L.S.: Claes Annerstedt 2p. Exchange of publications.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, Oct. 15, 1897; 8-3/4x5-3/4; Zoologisches zentralblatt
    Heidelberg, A.L.S.: A. Schuberg 1p., end. In German. Declines to exchange publications.
  - Letter to L. H. Houston [sic], Oct. 16, 1897; 7x4-1/2; Prime, Frederick, 1846-1915
    [Phila.] A.L.S. 1p. Asks for Library Committee meeting.
  - Letter to [George Henry] Horn, Oct. 16, [1897]; 8-3/4x5-3/4; Grote, Augustus Radcliffe, 1841-1903
    Hildesheim, A.L.S. 3p., end. Offers paper on specializations of the lepidopterous wing. For printed paper, see: APS Proceedings, vol. 37, pp. 17-44.
  - Letter to the [American philosophical society], Oct. 17, 1897; 9x5-3/4; Berliner Gesellschaft für Anthropologie, Ethnologie und Urgeschichte
    Berlin, A.L.S.: Max Bartels 1p., end. In German Cannot supply publication.
  - Letter to the [American philosophical society], Oct. 17, 1897; 11x8-1/2; Société de physique et d'histoire naturelle de Genève
    Geneva, A.L.S.: F. Louis Perrot 1p., end. In French Concerns missing publications. Written on verso of query. See A.P.S. to Société, Oct. 4, 1897.
  - Letter to I[saac] Minis Hays, Oct. 18, 1897; 8x5-1/4; Allen, Harrison, 1841-1897
    Phila., Typed L.S. 1p. Asks for Challenger reports. Refers to W. Turner's paper on Crania.
  - Letter to J [sic] Minis Hays, Oct. 18, 1897; 5-1/2x8; Houston, Edwin J. (Edwin James), 1847-1914
    Phila., Typed L.S. 1p. Library Committee meeting.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, Oct. 18, 1897; 11-3/4x9-1/4; Uppsala Universitetsbibliotek
    Upsala, Printed L. filled in in MS., S.: Claes Annerstedt 2p., end. Exchange of publications.
  - Letter to I[saac] Minis Hays, Oct. 19, 1897; 3-1/2x5-1/2; Allen, Harrison, 1841-1897
    Phila., A.L.S. on postal card 1p. and add. Concerns Challenger reports. Refers to W. Turner.
  - Letter to J [sic] Minis Hays, Oct. 19, 1897; 10x8; Institution of Mechanical Engineers (Great Britain)
    London, Typed L.S.: Alfred Bache 1p. Exchange of publications.
  - Letter to [Isaac Minis] Hays, Oct. 19, 1897; 8-1/2x5-1/2; Rosengarten, J. G. (Joseph George), 1835-1921
    Paris A.L.S. 2p. Encs. wanting Sends Ellis & Elvey's receipted bill. Refers to Bertin and French exchanges.
  - Letter to I[saac] Minis Hays, Oct. 19, 1897; 7x8; Squibb, E. H.
    Brooklyn, [N.Y.], Typed L.S. 1p. Thanks for E.R. Squibb's notice of election.
  - Telegram to the American philosophical society, Oct. 20, 1897; 5-1/4x8; Bunce, F. M.
    Navy Yard, Brooklyn, N.Y., D. 1p. Gives Peary's address.
  - Letter to Frederick Fraley, Oct. 20, 1897; 8-1/2x5-1/2; Ferguson, William A.
    New York, A.L.S. 1p. Inquires about Phillips prize.
  - Letter to Safety Storage Van & Packing Co., Phila., Oct. 20, 1897; 3-1/2x5-1/2; Patterson, Robert, 1819?-1909
    [Phila.] A.L.S. on postal card 1p. and add. Arrangements to pick up storage cabinet.
  - Letter to I[saac] Minis Hays, Oct. 20, 1897; 10-1/2x8; Smithsonian Institution
    Washington, Typed L.S.: Richard Rathbun 1p., end. Concerns missing package.
  - Letter to I[saac] Minis Hays, Oct. 20, 1897; 8-1/2x 5-1/2; Vaux, George
    Phila., A.L.S. 1p. Change of address.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, Oct. 21, 1897; 7x4-1/2; Bartholow, Roberts, 1831-1904
    Phila., A.L.S. 1p., end. Concerns Nansen Meeting.
  - Letter to J [sic] Minis Hays, Oct. 21, 1897; 11x8; Houston, Edwin J. (Edwin James), 1847-1914
    Phila., Typed L.S. 1p. Enc. wanting Cannot attend Library Committee meeting. Encloses letter from J.C. Morris. Refers to Curators.
  - Letter to J [sic] M[inis] Hays, Oct. 21, 1897; 11x8-1/2; Howe, Henry Marion, 1848-1922
    New York, Typed L.S. 1p. Thanks for election to membership.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, Oct. 22, 1897; 11-1/2x9; Bayerische Numismatische Gesellschaft
    Munich, L.S.: Eugen Merzbacher 1p. Declines to exchange publications.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, Oct. 22, 1897; 8-1/2x5-1/4; Cattell, James McKeen, 1860-1944
    Garrisons-on-Hudson, N.Y., L. 1p., end. Asks for list of A.P.S. members.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, Oct. 22, 1897; 3-3/4x5-1/2; Naturforschende Gesellschaft des Osterlandes zu Altenburg
    Altenburg, A.L.S.: Max Voretzsch, on postal card 1p., end., and add. In German Exchange of publications.
  - Telegram to J. Minis Hayes [sic], Oct. 22, 1897; 5-1/4x8; Peary, Robert E. (Robert Edwin), 1856-1920
    Brooklyn, N.Y., D. 1p. Cannot attend Nansen meeting.
  - Letter to J. Minis-Hays [sic], Oct. 23, 1897; 10-1/2x8; Melville, George W. (George Wallace), 1841-1912
    Washington, Typed L.S. 1p. Hopes to attend Nansen meeting.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, Oct. 23, 1897; 9x5-3/4; Königlich Bayerische Akademie der Wissenschaften
    Munich, L.S.: J[oseph] Aumer, Librarian 2p. Exchange of publications through J.G. Flügel.
  - Letter to I[saac] Minis Hays, Oct. 23, 1897; 7-1/4x4-1/2; Pettit, Henry, 1842-1921
    Overbrook, [Pa.] A.L.S. 2p. Enc. wanting Sends communication for Houston to be placed with records of Library Committee.
  - Letter to Fred[eric]k Fraley, Oct. 24, 1897; 6-3/4x4-1/2; Van Antwerp, William
    Tenafly, N.J., A.L.S. 1p., end. Inquires about Phillips prize.
  - Letter to Frederick Fraley, Oct. 25, 1897; 11x8-1/2; Frankenstein, Samuel I.
  - Letter to C. Stuart Patterson, Oct. 25, 1897; 10-1/2x8; Gale, Abel
    New York, Typed L.S. 1p., end. Inquires about Phillips prize. Written on same sheet is Patterson to E. Morrison, Oct. 26, 1897.
  - Letter to the [American philosophical society], Oct. 25, 1897; 5-3/4x8-1/2; McRae, W. P.
    Petersburg, Va., A.L.S. 1p., end. Inquires about Phillips prize.
  - Letter to C. Stuart Patterson, Oct. 25, 1897; 7-1/4x8-1/4; Mathews, Robert Valentine
    New York, A.L.S. 1p., end. Inquires about Phillips prize. Written on same sheet is letter from Patterson to [Ella] Morison, [Oct., 1897]
  - Letter to J [sic] Minis Hays, Oct. 25, 1897; 9x5-3/4; Nansen, Fridtjof, 1861-1930
    New York, L.S.: Lionel Clapham Secretary 1p. Arranges meeting.
  - Letter to Frederick Fraley, Oct. 25, 1897; 9x5-3/4; Perkins, D. W. (David Walter), b. 1851
    Manchester, N.H., A.L.S. 1p., end. Inquires about Phillips prize.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, Oct. 25, 1897; 10-3/4x8; Tesla, Nikola, 1856-1943
    New York, Typed L.S. 1p. Cannot attend Nansen Meeting.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, Oct. 25, 1897; Rand, Theodore D.
    A.L.S. 1p. Asks "if ladies will be expected at the meeting on Friday afternoon next and whether, if accompanying members, they will need cards of admission."
  - Letter to Frederick Fraley, Oct. 25, [1897]; 8x5; Gray, James McIlvaine, 1872-1942
    Brooklyn, [N.Y.], A.L.S. 1p., end. Inquires about Phillips prize.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, Oct. 26, 1897; 9x5-3/4; Culin, Stewart, 1858-1929
    Phila., A.L.S. 1p., end. Asks loan of two books.
  - Letter to [Isaac Minis] Hays, Oct. 26, 1897; 9x5-3/4; Mercer, Henry Chapman, 1856-1930
    Doylestown, Pa., L.S. 1p. Concerns objects to be photographed by Sachse.
  - Letter to [Ella M.] Morrison [sic], Oct. 26, 1897; 10-1/2x8; Patterson, Christopher Stuart, 1842-1924
    Phila., Typed L.S. 1p. Asks her to send Phillips prize circular to A. Gale. Written on same sheet as Gale to Patterson, Oct. 25, 1897.
  - Letter to the [American philosophical society], Oct. 26, 1897; 8-1/2x5-1/4; Kaiserl. Akademie der Wissenschaften in Wien
    L.S.: Emil [Viktor] Kohl 1p., end. Lacks Proceedings, No. 153.
  - Letter to I[saac] Minis Hays, Oct. 27, 1897; 8-1/4x5; Fraley, F. (Frederick), 1804-1901
    [Phila.], L. 1p. Encs. wanting Forwards applications for Phillips prize circulars.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, Oct. 27, 1897; 3-1/2x4-1/2; Haynes, Henry W. (Henry Williamson), 1831-1912
    Boston, A.L.S. 2p., end. Asks for copy of Cushing's paper. Refers to F.W. Putnam.
  - Letter to Geo[rge] F[rederick] Barker, Oct. 27, 1897; 10-1/2x8; Hunt, Charles Warren
    New York, Typed L.S. 1p. Enc. wanting Asks him to forward the enclosed.
  - Letter to J [sic] Minis Hays, Oct. 27, 1897; 8-1/4 x 5; Royal Photographic Society of Great Britain
    London, L.S.: R. Child Bayley 2p., end. Exchange of publications.
  - Letter to Frederick Fraley, Oct. 28, 1897; 8-1/2x5-1/2; Giddings, Edward F.
    Ann Arbor, Mich., A.L.S. 2p., end. Inquires about Phillips prize.
  - Letter to I[saac] M[inis] Hays, Oct. 28, 1897; 10x8; New York State Library
    Albany, N.Y., A.L.S.: S[tephen] B. Griswold, Law Libn. 1p., end. Exchange of publications.
  - Letter to [Isaac Minis] Hays, Oct. 28, 1897; 8x5; Scott, William Berryman, 1858-1947
    Princeton, [N.J.], A.L.S. 1p. Cannot attend Nansen Meeting.
  - Letter to Persifor Frazer, Oct. 29, 1897; 11x8-1/2; Peckham, Stephen Farnum, 1839-1918
    Ann Arbor, Mich., A.L.S. 1p. Thanks for membership certificate.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, Oct. 29, 1897; 10-1/2x8-1/4; Walker, Lewis Burd, 1855-1903
    Pottsville, Pa., A.L.S. 1p. Offers copy of his edition of William Allen's Letter Book. For copy, see B/A15w.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, Oct. 29, [1897]; 3-3/4x5-1/2; Schweizerische Naturforschende Gesellschaft
    Bern, Printed L. on postal card, filled in in MS. 1p., end., and add. In German Wants various Proceedings.
  - Letter to J. Minis-Hays [sic], Oct. 30, 1897; 10-1/2x8; Melville, George W. (George Wallace), 1841-1912
    Washington, Typed L.S. 1p. Explains abrupt departure from Nansen meeting. Refers to Heilprin.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, Oct. 30, 1897; 11-1/4x9; Naturhistorische Gesellschaft Nürnberg
    Nuremberg, A.L.S.: K. Hörmann, Librarian 1p., end. Exchange of publications.
  - Letter to [J. G.] Flügel, Leipzig, Oct. 31, 1897; 8-3/4x5-3/4; Reuleaux, F. (Franz), 1829-1905
    [Berlin?], A.L.S. 1p., end. Change of address. With English translations in Frazer's hand.
  - Letter to [Ella M.] Morison, Oct., 1897; 7-1/4x8-1/4; Patterson, Christopher Stuart, 1842-1924
    [Phila.,]. A.L.S. 1p. About Phillips prize. On same sheet as R.V. Mathews to Patterson, Oct. 25, 1897.
  - Letter to [Isaac Minis] Hays, Oct., [1897]; 8-1/2x5-1/2; Redpath Lyceum Bureau
    New York, A.L.S.: Richard Heard 1p. Concerns Nansen lecture.
  - Letter to [Isaac Minis] Hays, Oct., [1897]; 9-1/2x5-3/4; Heilprin, Angelo, 1853-1907
    Phila., Wednesday A.L.S. 4p. Concerns arrangements for Nansen meeting. "Nansen has a decided dislike to being bored..." Refers to Peary. Mentions own paper on African glaciation; see A.P.S. Proceedings, vol. 36, p.434.
  - Letter to Henry Phillips, Nov. 1, 1897; 3-1/2x5-1/2; Valuckas, Andrius
    Baltimore, A.L.S. on postal card. 1p., end., and add. In Esperanto. Asks for Phillips's translation of a work on international language. For translation, see Pamphlets, vol. 256, no. 25.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, Nov. 1, 1897; 10x8-1/2; Winand, Paul A. N.
    Phila., A.L.S. 1p. Concerns his part in discussion of Houston and Kennelly paper; see A.P.S. Proceedings, vol. 36, pp. 144-175.
  - Letter to I[saac] M[inis] Hays, Nov. 1, [1897]; 3-1/2x5-1/2; John Wanamaker (Firm)
    Phila., L. on postal card 1p. About order for Sabin.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, Nov. 2, 1897; 11-1/4x9; Deutsche Akademie der Wissenschaften zu Berlin
    Berlin, L.S.: Vahlen 1p., end. In German Exchange of publications.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, Nov. 2, 1897; 9-1/2x6; Marks, A. J.
    Toledo, O., A.L.S. 1p., end. Inquires about Cushing's paper on excavations in Florida. For printed paper, see: APS Proceedings vol. 35, pp. 329-448.
  - Letter to I[saac] Minis Hays, Nov. 3, 1897; 9-1/4x6; Brown, Ernest W. (Ernest William), 1866-1938
    Haverford, Pa., A.L.S. 1p. Concerns F. Morley's membership certificate.
  - Letter to Frederick Fraley, Nov. 3, 1897; 11x8-1/4; Eldridge, D. A.
    Dallas, Tex., Typed L.S. 1p., end. Inquires about Phillips prize.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, Nov. 3, 1897; 7x5-1/4; Ganse, Anton
    Graz, A.L.S. 1p. Sends copy of his Das Weltprincip und die transcendentale Logik.
  - Letter to Frederick Fraley, Nov. 3, 1897; 5-1/2x8-1/2; Potter, Ralph F.
    Bloomington, Ill., Typed L.S. 1p., end. Inquires about Phillips prize.
  - Letter to E[lla M.] Morrison [sic], Nov. 4, 1897; 9-1/2x6; Johnson, T. & J. W.
    Phila., L. 1p., end. Business matter.
  - Letter to J. Minis-Hays [sic], Nov. 4, 1897; 10-1/2x8; Melville, George W. (George Wallace), 1841-1912
    Washington, Typed L.S. 1p. Enc. wanting Sends revised copy of his remarks at Nansen meeting. For printed paper, see: APS Proceedings vol. 36, pp. 454-461.
  - Letter to J [sic] Minis Hays, Nov. 4, 1897; 11x8-1/2; Pennsylvania. State Library
    Harrisburg, Pa., Typed L.S.: William H[enry] Egle 1p. Will supply State Archives.
  - Letter to Frederick Fraley, Nov. 5, 1897; 11x8-1/2; Adams, Edwin G.
    Newark, N.J., Typed L.S. 1p., end. Inquires about Phillips prize essay.
  - Letter to I[saac] Minis Hays, Nov. 5, 1897; 13x8; Hildeburn, Charles Swift Riché, 1855-1901
    Phila., Typed L.S. 1p., end. Concerns library's set of Sabin.
  - Letter to Frederick Fraley, Nov. 5, 1897; 5-1/2x8-1/2; Ironside, C. N.
    New York, Typed L.S. 1p., end. Inquires about Phillips prize
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, Nov. 6, 1897; 9x5-3/4; Culin, Stewart, 1858-1929
    Phila., A.L.S. 1p. Asks for copy of APS Library Catalogue.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, Nov. 6, 1897; 9x5-3/4; Williams, Talcott, 1849-1928
    Phila., A.L.S. 1p. Asks that Petermann's Mitheilungen be added to library.
  - Letter to I[saac] Minnis [sic] Hays, Nov. 8, 1897; 8-1/4x5, 10-3/4x8-1/2; C. J. Clay and Sons
    London, L. 2p. Enc. of 2p. printed prospectus Concerns Catalogue of Scientific Papers of the Royal Society.
  - Letter to Persifor Frazer, Nov. 8, 1897; 8-1/2x7-1/2; Mabery, Charles Frederic, 1850-
    Cleveland, O., Typed L.S. with MS. corrections 1p., end. Acknowledges receipt of diploma. Mentions Sadtler's paper on petroleum.
  - Letter to I[saac] Minis Hays, Nov. 8, 1897; 9x5-3/4; Pettit, Henry, 1842-1921
    Phila., A.L.S. 1p. Give portraits of Priestley and Rittenhouse to Earle & sons for cleaning.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, Nov. 8, [1897]; 7-1/4x5-3/4; Offenbach verein für naturkunde
    Offenbach a.M., A.L.S.: [Wilhelm] Storck 2p., end. In German Annual Reports out of print.
  - Letter to I[saac] Minis Hays, Nov. 9, 1897; 9x5-3/4; Culin, Stewart, 1858-1929
    Phila., A.L.S. 1p. Thanks for A.P.S. Library Catalogue.
  - Letter to J [sic] Minis Hays, Nov. 9, 1897; 5-1/2x8; Houston, Edwin J. (Edwin James), 1847-1914
    Phila., Typed L.S. with MS. addition 1p. Calls Library Committee meeting.
  - Letter to [Isaac Minis] Hays, Nov. 9, 1897; 8-1/2x5-1/2; Mercer, Henry Chapman, 1856-1930
    Doylestown, Pa., L.S. 1p. Concerns portraits and busts of Cope.
  - Letter to Frederick Fraley, Nov. 9, 1897; 5-1/2x8-1/2; Shabad, Henry M.
    Chicago, Typed L.S. 1p., end. Inquires about Phillips prize.
  - Letter to J.M. Hay [sic], Nov. 10, 1897; 3-1/2x5-1/2; Walker, Lewis Burd, 1855-1903
    Pottsville, A.L.S. on postal card 1p. and add. Book has been sent.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, Nov. 10, 1897; 8-1/2x5-1/2; Wells, Philip P. (Philip Patterson), 1868-1929
    New Haven, Conn., A.L.S. 1p., end. Inquires about Phillips prize.
  - Letter to the [American philosophical society], Nov. 11, 1897; 10x8; Mitchell, S. D.
    Pittsburgh, Pa. A.L.S. 1p., end. Inquires about Phillips prize.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, Nov. 11, 1897; 8-3/4x5-3/4; Renevier, Eugène, 1831-1906
    Lausanne, A.L.S. 2p., end. Asks for Proceedings lacking from his set.
  - Letter to J [sic] Minis Hays, Nov. 12, 1897; 8-3/4x5-3/4; Grote, Augustus Radcliffe, 1841-1903
    Hildesheim, A.L.S. 3p. Horn's illness. Concerns illustrations for proposed paper.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, Nov. 12, 1897; 14x8-1/2; Guatemala. Dirección General de Estadística
    Printed L. filled in in MS., S.: Padilla 1p., end. Has been appointed Director General.
  - Letter to J [sic] Minis Hays, Nov. 12, 1897; 10x8; Institute of Jamaica
    Kingston, Jamaica, L.S.: Frank Cundall 1p., end. Exchange of publications.
  - Letter to [Isaac Minis] Hays, Nov. 12, 1897; 8-1/4x5; Jastrow, Morris, 1861-1921
    [Phila.], A.L.S. 1p. Concerns his paper on Hebrew Sabbath. See: APS Proceedings, vol. 36, p.499.
  - Letter to C. Stuart Patterson, Nov. 12, 1897; 10-1/4x8-1/4; Kohler, Max J. (Max James), 1871-1934
  - Letter to the [American philosophical society], Nov. 12, 1897; 8x5; Royal Astronomical Society
    London, A.L.S.: H[erbert] H[all] Turner 2p., end. Exchange of publications.
  - Letter to the University of Pennsylvania, Nov. 12, 1897; 5-3/4x6-1/2; E. Steiger & Co.
    New York, Printed L. filled in in MS. 1p., end. Order for Report of Babylonian Expedition.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, Nov. 13, 1897; 10-3/4x8-1/4; Dodge, Edmund R.
    Reno, Nev., Typed L.S. 1p., end. Inquires about Phillips prize.
  - Letter to William Pepper, Nov. 14, 1897; 7x4-1/2; Darwin, George Howard, Sir, 1845-1912
    Cambridge, Mass., A.L.S. 3p. and end. Concerns invitation to speak before A.P.S.
  - Letter to the [American philosophical society], Nov. 15, 1897; 9-1/2x6; Craig & Evans
    Phila., L. 1p., end. Sends for Cope portrait, to be delivered to the Academy of Natural Sciences.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, Nov. 15, 1897; 10-1/2x8-1/4; Fowler, Charles S.
    Albany, N.Y., A.L.S. 1p., end. Inquires about Phillips prize.
  - Letter to I[saac] Minis Hays, Nov. 15, 1897; 3-1/2x5-1/2; Lyman, Benjamin Smith, 1835-1920
    Phila., A.L.S. on postal card 1p. and add. Postpones reading of paper by Mr. Wadamori.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, Nov. 15, 1897; 10-1/2x8-1/4; Royal Society of New South Wales
    [Sydney], L.S.: Geo[rge] H[andley] Knibbs 1p. Exchange of publications.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, Nov. 15, 1897; 10x8; Weigle, Gilbert G.
    Palo Alto, Cal., A.L.S. 1p., end. Inquires about Phillips prize.
  - Letter to the [American philosophical society], Nov. 16, 1897; 7x4-1/2; Asiatic Society of Japan
    Tokyo, Printed L. filled in in ms., S.: E[rnest] W. Clement 2p., end. Exchange of publications.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, Nov. 16, 1897; 11x8-1/2; Pohli, Emil
    San Francisco, [Cal.], A.L.S. 1p., end. Inquires about Phillips prize.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, Nov. 16, 1897; 11x8; Smith, McNutt & Hannon
    Los Angeles, Cal. Typed L. 1p., end. Inquires about Phillips prize.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, Nov. 16, 1897; 10-1/2x8; Smithsonian Institution
    Washington, Typed L.S.: Richard Rathbun 1p. Concerns Bolton's Catalogue of Scientific and Technical Periodicals.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, Nov. 16, 1897; 11x8-1/2; E. Steiger & Co.
    New York, L. 1p. Offers to supply foreign books.
  - Letter to [William Pepper], Nov. 17, 1897; 7x4-1/2; Darwin, George Howard, Sir, 1845-1912
    New York, A.L.S. 1p. and end. Cannot speak to A.P.S.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, Nov. 17, 1897; 11x8-1/2, 5-1/2x8-1/2; Howe addressing company
    Typed L. 2 items 2p. Business letters.
  - Letter to [Isaac Minis] Hays, Nov. 17, 1897; 8-1/4x5; Jastrow, Morris, 1861-1921
    [Phila.], A.L.S. 2p. Concerns his paper on the Hebrew Sabbath. See: APS Proceedings, vol. 36, p. 499.
  - Letter to [Isaac Minis] Hays, Nov. 17, 1897; 9x5-3/4; Mercer, Henry Chapman, 1856-1930
    Doylestown, Pa., L.S. 1p.., end. Concerns proofs.
  - Letter to the American philosophical society, Nov. 17, 1897; 8x5; Yorkshire Geological and Polytechnic Society
    Hopton, [Eng.], A.L.S.: W. Lowes Carter 1p., end. Exchange of publications.
  - Letter to [Isaac Minis Hays], Nov. 18, [1897]; 9x5-3/4; Nelson, William, 1847-1914
    Paterson, N. J., Typed L.S. 1p., end. Inquires about early N.J. newspapers. Refers to J.W. Jordan.